<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ranhya</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ranhya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2025 Ranhya</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cat Quest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cat-quest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cat-quest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[img]
Peak gaming. Cat Quest is a game I remember from when I was a little girl—and seeing it on sale for super cheap I nabbed it. It was a great decision. I remembered this game very fondly and I’m glad to report that it is not nostalgia this game slaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gameplay loop is addictive and keeps you playing, I played it for 10 hours and got the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/y6QPlokR4M4&#34;&gt;platinum&lt;/a&gt;, couldn’t put the game down for those 10 hours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[img]
Peak gaming. Cat Quest is a game I remember from when I was a little girl—and seeing it on sale for super cheap I nabbed it. It was a great decision. I remembered this game very fondly and I’m glad to report that it is not nostalgia this game slaps.</p>
<p>The gameplay loop is addictive and keeps you playing, I played it for 10 hours and got the <a href="https://youtu.be/y6QPlokR4M4">platinum</a>, couldn’t put the game down for those 10 hours.</p>
<h2 id="combat">Combat</h2>
<p>The combat system is incredibly polished and the movement attacking and using spells all feel very good. It’s very satisfying killing groups of enemies and collecting EXP and coins dropped from enemies forces my brain to literally ooze dopamine from my pores it’s just that good.</p>
<p>The spells are very thought out thought a lot of them are outshined by 3 spells specifically. You can get every spell after beating the first main boss in the game (dragon) which is cool. Though the most useful ones so heavily outshine the other ones that I ended up using 3 spells nearing the end off the game… and was melting bosses way above my own level, skull icon and all.</p>
<p>The game isn’t super difficult obviously, it doesn’t need to be. But it provides enough of a challenge to keep you engaged and the combat loop is super fun. Repetitive? Yes but the game is short enough that I never once got bored of just killing things. Even just grinding felt fun.</p>
<p>I really love the spells and I think they’re super cool because of the way they work. You have 5 damage spells available to you: fire, ice, lighting, trap and a purple magic idk what it is lol. The thing I really like about them is that they all have different patterns they hit in! Lighting hits to the sides of your character while ice hits in the front and in the back, fire is a big AOE circle and the purple magic thing hits in an X shape. The trap magic is special as it leaves a spike trap behind that lasts a few seconds and hurts the enemies that stand on it.</p>
<p>Other than those you have a healing spell which becomes less and less useful as you become more powerful and, the most broken ability in the game—an ability that gives you a percentage boost to your damage, all of it. At max level I think it’s like an 100% boost and it is BROKEN. It only consumes a sliver of your mana so you can spam it in every encounter and absolutely melt every enemy with lighting and fire spells (they deal the most damage)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grand Theft Auto 5’s missions suck</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gta5-missions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gta5-missions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a really long time since I last played GTA 5 so I barely remember anything, but a GTA 5 video came up in my YouTube recommendations and the thought came to my mind, GTA 5’s missions fucking SUCK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s not that many good missions in the game with the heists being somewhat decent, and even those don’t have much going for them. The missions of the game just feel like “drive to this place, watch cutscene, shoot people, watch cutscene, mission passed”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It has been a really long time since I last played GTA 5 so I barely remember anything, but a GTA 5 video came up in my YouTube recommendations and the thought came to my mind, GTA 5’s missions fucking SUCK.</p>
<p>There’s not that many good missions in the game with the heists being somewhat decent, and even those don’t have much going for them. The missions of the game just feel like “drive to this place, watch cutscene, shoot people, watch cutscene, mission passed”</p>
<p>There’s zero substance to the missions and basically 0 player agency, it feels like if you just turn around in the wrong direction you fail the mission. The script of the missions is beyond insane with literally all of the agency taken away from the player.</p>
<p>As testament to how scripted the game is: it took 12 years for speedrunners to figure out how to skip the long ass train cutscene in prologue.</p>
<p>And besides 4, it is also the only 3D GTA game that does not have insane on mission 0 glitches.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blacklist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/offtopic/the-blacklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/offtopic/the-blacklist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;![[The_Blacklist.jpeg]]
The Blacklist is an interesting show, it’s right up my alley, and has done quite well to the point that other shows seem to have taken from it. (I say this because I have a feeling the J-Drama Invisible (インビジブル) might have taken inspiration from it as they have an identical premise)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post will just be a collection of my thoughts on the show, therefore &lt;strong&gt;&lt;mark style=“color:red;”&gt;it will contain lots of spoilers&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. So if you don’t want that I recommend you do watch the show first as it is actually a really good show!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>![[The_Blacklist.jpeg]]
The Blacklist is an interesting show, it’s right up my alley, and has done quite well to the point that other shows seem to have taken from it. (I say this because I have a feeling the J-Drama Invisible (インビジブル) might have taken inspiration from it as they have an identical premise)</p>
<p>This post will just be a collection of my thoughts on the show, therefore <strong><mark style=“color:red;”>it will contain lots of spoilers</mark></strong>. So if you don’t want that I recommend you do watch the show first as it is actually a really good show!</p>
<p>I will update the post with my thoughts as I keep watching.</p>
<h2 id="season-1">Season 1</h2>
<p>Season 1 is merely an introduction that sets the story in motion it seems. The main plot in season 1 revolves around Red giving the task force a bunch of targets whom are seemingly disconnected but at the end we find out that they are all actually connected to the entity we now know as Berlin.</p>
<p>The thing Liz is really annoying in season 1 at times being butthurt over crazy things. And it’s clear from the start that Tom is weird. One thing about Tom is that I can’t see him as Tom Keen and instead in my head he’s Max Fosh from New Amsterdam which makes no sense in this story because he is a horrible criminal who’s done horrible things lol.</p>
<p><em>also my prediction is that Liz will end up with Ressler they’ve been setting this up, Aubrey getting killed off was what made it clear to me. Though I don’t know whether or not it’s gonna happen yet obviously… I give it a 9/10 chance</em></p>
<h2 id="season-2">Season 2</h2>
<p>The start of the season focuses on finding Berlin and Liz coming to terms with what has happened to her—with Tom and with her father.</p>
<p>I think it’s quite a shame that Malik died I quite liked her character but Samar seems to be her replacement I guess, colored woman must replace other colored woman of course (lol). Samar is cool though I like her character so far.</p>
<p>Liz’s character arc continues as well, now she’s paranoid, sleeping in motels, using aliases… sleeping with a gun. She’s kind of a badass though.</p>
<p>Naomi/Carla is a fucking bitch along with her stupid ass husband, your life is in danger but you refuse to listen to the one guy who can keep you safe, it’s so fucking stupid dude what the hell. Like I guess that it’s a complicated past and stuff but that shouldn’t matter when your life is in danger and you know that Red only wants to help you fucking stay alive.</p>
<p>I mean the only reason she got grabbed in the first place was because she was being a stubborn motherfucker, if you are in protective custody and the FBI comes to tell you that you are in danger you go with them NO QUESTIONS ASKED it’s kinda stupid that she just stood there talking like bruh go already.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Trigger</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/offtopic/world-trigger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/offtopic/world-trigger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/World_Trigger.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;World Trigger.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://anilist.co/manga/78151/&#34;&gt;World Trigger&lt;/a&gt; is a super underrated shounen battle anime in my opinion. I don’t hear people talking about it like at all even though it’s probably one of the best in the genre. World Trigger has amazing characters and a banger power system—and an interesting plot to top it all off of course. The world building is nothing to scoff at and the show is filled TO THE BRIM with tournament arcs, which we all know everyone loves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/World_Trigger.jpeg" alt="World Trigger.jpeg">
<a href="https://anilist.co/manga/78151/">World Trigger</a> is a super underrated shounen battle anime in my opinion. I don’t hear people talking about it like at all even though it’s probably one of the best in the genre. World Trigger has amazing characters and a banger power system—and an interesting plot to top it all off of course. The world building is nothing to scoff at and the show is filled TO THE BRIM with tournament arcs, which we all know everyone loves.</p>
<p>The main focus of the fights is less on power of friendship suddenly get a boost in strength and instead the focus is on actual strategy and planning with some really cool fights emerging from it. The main character is the stereotypical weak can’t do anything typo of shounen character but instead of powering up significantly he uses his other advantage such as his ability to think clearly under pressure and surprising knowledge of battle tactics along with the advantages of his teammates to form strategies in order to win against the opponents.</p>
<p>One thing I really like in this show is that the characters actually listen to each other and also respect orders, they don’t do bullshit because they don’t want to or anything.</p>
<p>World Trigger is a piece of media I highly recommend. I do recommend you watch the anime first, though it starts of pretty slowly—the manga has the same issue though. You can watch the anime and then start the manga from where the anime left off though as the anime adaptation is very faithful to the original you won’t miss out on anything!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>baka</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/offtopic/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/offtopic/test/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;kono baka ga!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>kono baka ga!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bloodborne</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bloodborne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bloodborne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Bloodborne.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Bloodborne.jpeg&#34;&gt;
If this game got a sequel it would be more than a masterpiece. And I do believe it. The game has a lot going for it despite it having a lot of flaws, if I’d written this post a few years ago I think it’d be very different but having now played through Sekiro, Elden Ring and Dark Souls 3 (I’ll go back to ds1 and 2 eventually)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can say that while this isn’t my favorite game fromsoft has made it is still amazing and still holds up even after all these years. Though it’s being heavily held back by the lack of a rerelease on better hardware. I actually tried replaying the game before writing this post but I just could not do it—30fps is just too shit to do this game justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/Bloodborne.jpeg" alt="Bloodborne.jpeg">
If this game got a sequel it would be more than a masterpiece. And I do believe it. The game has a lot going for it despite it having a lot of flaws, if I’d written this post a few years ago I think it’d be very different but having now played through Sekiro, Elden Ring and Dark Souls 3 (I’ll go back to ds1 and 2 eventually)</p>
<p>I can say that while this isn’t my favorite game fromsoft has made it is still amazing and still holds up even after all these years. Though it’s being heavily held back by the lack of a rerelease on better hardware. I actually tried replaying the game before writing this post but I just could not do it—30fps is just too shit to do this game justice.</p>
<h2 id="the-gameplay">The Gameplay</h2>
<p>It’s the main appeal of any fromsoft game… obviously you don’t play this game for the story. <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>Bloodborne compared to the other games fromsoft has made is very unique, not quite as unique as Sekiro which I consider to be a completely different genre but in comparison to the Dark Souls trilogy it is very different.</p>
<p>The most obvious difference is the setting, but I will talk about that a bit later.</p>
<h3 id="the-combat">The Combat</h3>
<p>Bloodborne’s combat is very fast paced compared to Dark Souls 1 and 2, the main dodging mechanic when locked on goes from a roll to a dash—everyone’s already said this though.</p>
<p>And the weapon mechanics are completely different, as every weapon has two modes—this adds a lot more to the movesets compared to the Dark Souls games where each weapon has a pretty simple moveset.</p>
<p>The weapon I ended up using the most during my 150 hours of playtime was the saw cleaver as it’s probably one of the best weapons in the game. The transformation attacks are very powerful and build up beast blood meter very quickly and all that—plus the extra damage against beasts is nice.</p>
<p>Beast blood pellets increase the damage you do at the cost of increasing the damage you take as well, and they are the most broken item in this game by far allowing you to melt bosses and stun lock some with limb breaks. It’s what makes the saw cleaver such a good weapon as the transformation attack R1-L1 allows you to build up beast blood meter very quickly, the higher the bar the more damage you do but also the more damage you take.</p>
<p>The game has a unique limb break mechanic which allows you to break a boss’s limbs and stagger them, this mechanic is absolutely broken and allows you to stun lock certain bosses.</p>
<h3 id="the-bosses">The Bosses</h3>
<p>This is the base game’s worst area in my opinion—there’s just not that many good bosses compared to the bad ones, and the really good bosses you might just miss if you don’t explore enough. I don’t have the DLC so I’ll only be talking about the base game bosses. From what I’ve seen the DLC doesn’t have this issue and it has some of the best bosses.</p>
<p>Martyr Logarius is in my opinion the best boss in the base game, and it is an optional boss that’s actually very easy to miss as it’s a pain in the ass to even get to him. You have to parkour over rooftops and all of that in an optional area.</p>
<p>And his run back is absolutely excruciating but it is absolutely worth it as this boss is actually awesome.</p>
<p>Some other good bosses include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Blood starved Beast, which is optional but you probably won’t miss it on your first playthrough and it’s a boss that’s even fought in the speedrun of the game because it allows access to a shortcut.</li>
<li>Father Gascoigne obviously duh</li>
<li>Gehrman the First Hunter obviously</li>
<li>And the Shadows of Yharnam</li>
</ul>
<p>As for the worst boss in the game the award has to go to—not Micolash, I actually quite like his fight but rather it goes to… The One Reborn.</p>
<p>This boss just sucks, it’s not hard, it’s not unique it is just meh. It can be annoying as he can do super bullshit moves that you can’t dodge, you have to kill stupid mages at the top every time if you want to do that though it’s just a waste of time because you can melt the boss in seconds with limb breaks and beast blood pellets.</p>
<p>It’s essentially just the limb break boss.</p>
<h2 id="the-setting">The Setting</h2>
<p>The setting and the levels, along with the lore in this one is top notch. I didn’t really care much about Dark Souls 3 lore or Elden Ring lore, but Bloodborne is the only fromsoft game where I actually cared about the lore.</p>
<p>I don’t really remember anything since it’s been so long but the lore for this game is actually really awesome, and I just think the lovecraftian type stuff it’s got going is really cool.</p>
<p>The thing I don’t like about the levels is that it is always just so dark and gloomy… I know that that’s how it’s supposed to be considering the game takes place at night, and the night doesn’t end until you finish the game.</p>
<p>But I just tend to hate when stuff is always dark and gloomy without any break from the gloominess. It’s just a me issue though.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>I do really recommend you check out a lore video on YouTube after playing the game though as it is incredibly interesting.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hades</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hades/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Hades.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Hades.jpeg&#34;&gt;
I’m a sucker for a good roguelite and Hades is one of the best, and also one of the most unique. Hades is one of the first (if not the first) roguelites to have a very prominent story. The story is built around you dying and interacting with the different NPCs at the house of Hades. &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/SupergiantGames/status/1343986323007238144&#34;&gt;The game has a total of 21,020 voice lines and 30 voiced characters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Hades_voiceover_stats.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Hades voiceover stats.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/Hades.jpeg" alt="Hades.jpeg">
I’m a sucker for a good roguelite and Hades is one of the best, and also one of the most unique. Hades is one of the first (if not the first) roguelites to have a very prominent story. The story is built around you dying and interacting with the different NPCs at the house of Hades. <a href="https://x.com/SupergiantGames/status/1343986323007238144">The game has a total of 21,020 voice lines and 30 voiced characters</a>.<img src="/images/Hades_voiceover_stats.jpeg" alt="Hades voiceover stats.jpeg"></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-combat">The Combat</h2>
<p>Hades’s combat is fast paced and satisfying—though it really makes my hands hurt! There 6 weapons all with 4 different aspects each. The aspects change the way the weapons are played and provide even more variety—you could say the game has 24 weapons in fact and it wouldn’t be wrong.</p>
<p>My favorite of these being the bow, specifically with the aspect of Hera. I’m generally a sucker for bows so any game with a bow gets extra points from me. The aspect of Hera allows you to load your casts into your bow and deal a FUCKTON and a TRUCKLOAD of burst damage which is super duper fun.</p>
<p>The number 2 spot has to go to the sword with Zagreus’ aspect, it’s basic but a lot of fun especially with the right build. It’s also the weapon I got my first and only sub 10 speedrun time with! I would’ve done more speedruns but the game really hurts my hands to play and I had moved on to other games after getting that run. Either way I’m very proud of it.</p>
<h2 id="the-story">The Story</h2>
<p>It’s been a while since I played the game so I don’t remember every detail but the story in this game is great! It takes place over the course of multiple runs. It takes 10 completed runs to get to the credits but it could take well over 100+ runs to get to the final epilogue, which I did as I have platinumed the game and have done basically everything there is to do.</p>
<p>You play as Zagreus, the not so well known son of Hades as he tries to escape the Hades underworld with the help of his relatives, the other gods.</p>
<h2 id="roguelite-gameplay">Roguelite Gameplay</h2>
<p>In order to get stronger in each run, you will collect boons from the gods which have various effects and stuff. The boons will for the most part affect one part of your kit and once a boon from a god is chosen it’s pretty difficult to get rid of as it will fill the slot of it’s type and you will only be able to replace it with another god’s boon of the same time if you get lucky. You can have boons from at most 4 gods in a single run.</p>
<p>Runs can actually be seeded, if you play a run and use the “give up” option in the menu then the run is not actually reset and if you start again it will give you the same RNG as the previous run. That’s why in speedruns you see runners dying before their attempts as dying does not have this effect and you get a completely new run.</p>
<p>Even though this is a roguelite, you can actually make builds somewhat effectively as you do get a choice between 3 boon and also a choice between which gods you choose, at least somewhat. The game has keepsakes—if you equip a god’s keepsake before starting the run that god will appear in the starting room and you can reset until you get the boon you desire. Builds center around 1 or 2 powerful boons and everything else you take will usually be to support those.</p>
<p>During runs you will also find hammers that change your weapon’s moveset and mechanics—and so that adds yet even more playstyles! You are guaranteed to see 2 hammers during your playthrough, though whether you choose to take them is up to you usually.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Persona 5 Royal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/persona-5-royal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/persona-5-royal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Persona_5_Royal.png&#34; alt=&#34;Persona 5 Royal.png&#34;&gt;
One of the most stylish games of the decade, and a masterpiece in story telling and JRPG gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game starts you off right in the action, right in one of the game’s last dungeons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only like 100 hours in you end up back at this point and it is the coolest thing ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-premise&#34;&gt;The Premise&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You play as Joker, a high schooler who after a tussle with a man heckling a woman—gets sent off to Tokyo to stay with a family friend, Sakura Sojiro… with a new and shiny criminal record to boot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/Persona_5_Royal.png" alt="Persona 5 Royal.png">
One of the most stylish games of the decade, and a masterpiece in story telling and JRPG gameplay.</p>
<hr>
<p>The game starts you off right in the action, right in one of the game’s last dungeons.</p>
<p>Only like 100 hours in you end up back at this point and it is the coolest thing ever.</p>
<h2 id="the-premise">The Premise</h2>
<p>You play as Joker, a high schooler who after a tussle with a man heckling a woman—gets sent off to Tokyo to stay with a family friend, Sakura Sojiro… with a new and shiny criminal record to boot.</p>
<p>On the first day of school you meet your soon to be best bro Sakamoto Ryuji, and somehow accidentally—you end up in the game’s first dungeon.</p>
<p>And so the story begins… not quite yet. The start of the game is painfully slow, though that is a problem with all the Persona games (excluding 1 and 2, those are way more bearable.)</p>
<p>It takes a couple of hours of tutorials and confused characters to actually finally start the first dungeon of the game—which you now know of as a “palace…”</p>
<h2 id="palaces">Palaces</h2>
<p>Kamoshida’s Palace and story is the main hook of the game. It’s the beginning dungeon obviously, but I do believe it’s also one of the best and of course it’s what sets the story in motion and helps form the Phantom Thieves.</p>
<p>Compared to the rest of the palaces it is a lot more basic with not a lot of special mechanics, but it doesn’t need them. The story establishes Kamoshida as a villain from basically the very start and it feels so good to finally take his ass down.</p>
<p>It’s always best to beat a palace immediately—go in on day one and make it to the treasure in one day, then the next you send the calling card and get it over with in 2 days. The reason being is that you will get the most free time in this way to do over-world activities.</p>
<p>I believe in the original this was a lot more difficult, however Royal made it a piece of cake to do this and it really isn’t that much of a challenge. Which kind of sucks but I will talk about that later in this post.</p>
<p>Each palace has its own special mechanics and all of them have absolutely amazing environments and art of course. They all offer unique challenges through puzzles and other sorts of mechanics, though most of the puzzles are not very difficult. The puzzles do get more complicated as you progress through the game—with the very last palace in the game, all the way in the second semester having the hardest puzzles in my opinion… though they’re still not too difficult which sucks. That being said the palaces are obviously super fun to navigate and offer enough challenge to keep you entertained.</p>
<h2 id="the-overworld">The Overworld</h2>
<p>In between dungeon exploration and story cutscenes—you get to free roam the Tokyo overworld, with more and more places available to you as you progress through the story. This is where you will be spending a lot of your playtime, doing confidants—leveling up your social stats and preparing for the various dungeons of the game.</p>
<p>The environments are obviously amazing, I mean especially in this art style the environments just feel awesome to be in and explore. The place you’ll be visiting most often is one of the streets of Shibuya and the underground mall—it’s the first place you’re introduced to outside of the school and Leblanc.</p>
<h2 id="the-confidants">The Confidants</h2>
<p>There are a total of 23 confidants in the game—and they are 100% possible to max out on your first play-through, and it’s super easy too, compared to the original Persona 5, you get way more time to do stuff in Royal. You don’t even need to follow a guide to the T or anything you can just wing it and you’ll probably be fine as long as you follow a few principles and know about some important mechanics. I’ll write another article detailing those and link it in the Related Articles at the bottom!</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/zkXiGMjm2SY">I did them all before even finishing the first semester so I even had a lot of time left over</a></p>
<h2 id="the-difficulty">The Difficulty</h2>
<p>The biggest issue the game has in my opinion is that it is very easy. The only boss that gave me trouble the very first time I played the game was Okumura and even then it was not that big of a deal—I just was not prepared for the fight at all was the issue.</p>
<p>Especially if you know what you’re doing the game becomes a pushover—though that’s not that big of a deal. Even with the game not being super difficult you can make it more challenging for yourself if you add a few restrictions.</p>
<p>If it’s your first playthrough and care about difficulty—I recommend playing on hard and not merciless, the reason for that is that merciless also doubles all damage on weaknesses, technicals and all that stuff… including the damage you and your party members take from these. However this is a blessing that makes fights a lot easier if you know what you’re doing. Hard doesn’t have this so it’s probably the hardest difficulty.</p>
<p>All in all the difficulty isn’t really an issue as the game isn’t meant to be the most difficult. I heard that the original is harder. Part of what makes it harder is that you get kicked out of the palace when you reach 100% on the security gauge so you have to be careful of that and it can ruin your 1 day run. Royal doesn’t have this so reaching 100% security gauge will do nothing more than increase the amount of enemies you fight.</p>
<h2 id="the-soundtrack">The Soundtrack</h2>
<p>Persona 5 Royal has one of my favorite soundtracks in any game and I still listen to songs from it regularly. It’s an amazing soundtrack that fits the vibe of the game perfectly and adds so much charm to the game it’s absolutely amazing. During battles I was just singing along having the time of my life listening to the songs. And near the end of the first semester the main boss theme changes and hearing it for the first time while fighting these cool-ass bosses was so awesome.</p>
<p>Beneath the Mask is an amazing song that fits the night Tokyo vibe and the theme of the game a lot, and the rain version without the lyrics is just <em>chefs kiss</em>, the cherry on top.</p>
<p>Oh yeah speaking of the rain + Beneath the Mask is such a calming combo the very first time I played the game when I was no-lifeing it, I would just fall asleep with the game in the background on a rainy day.</p>
<h4 id="related-articles">Related Articles</h4>
<p><a href="/hidden/p5r-tips/">Persona 5 Royal: Tips for All Confidants MAX</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Persona 5 Royal: Tips for All Confidants MAX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/hidden/p5r-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/hidden/p5r-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ll be detailing a few tips on getting all of your confidants to MAX in Persona 5 Royal. This can be done on your first playthrough with ease if you just keep a few things in mind. This is a lot more lenient than in the original Persona 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always carry a persona of the same arcana as the confidant you’re about to hang out with, this increases the amount of points you get.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On that note you should always pick the best dialogue option for the most points. You can easily Google these or once you have it you can use Chihaya’s last ability to tell you which ones to choose. Obviously googling is better as you don’t have to spend 10k yen for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prioritize hanging out with confidants over everything else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books are amazing, ideally you read them after reading the speed reading book you can get from the school library on and after July 1st. But you can probably do it before if you have time, especially on the days you get to read on the train. So you will ideally always have an unread book available for those days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Big Bang Burger Challenge is really good for stats, just make sure you can pass it before trying. It will give you points in every stat every time you pass it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;USE CHIHAYA!!! When you unlock her you should get her up ASAP as she has super duper useful abilities. Some confidants will have events where you cannot get enough points in order to advance them the next time you hang out, so it will waste time. However with Chihaya you can avoid this completely by using her abilities, specifically her rank 5 one which will increase your affinity with a confidant of your choice, doing this does not advance time and you can use it to avoid having to do extra hangouts with confidants and waste days. Her other abilities are very useful too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ll be detailing a few tips on getting all of your confidants to MAX in Persona 5 Royal. This can be done on your first playthrough with ease if you just keep a few things in mind. This is a lot more lenient than in the original Persona 5.</p>
<ul>
<li>Always carry a persona of the same arcana as the confidant you’re about to hang out with, this increases the amount of points you get.</li>
<li>On that note you should always pick the best dialogue option for the most points. You can easily Google these or once you have it you can use Chihaya’s last ability to tell you which ones to choose. Obviously googling is better as you don’t have to spend 10k yen for it.</li>
<li>Prioritize hanging out with confidants over everything else</li>
<li>Books are amazing, ideally you read them after reading the speed reading book you can get from the school library on and after July 1st. But you can probably do it before if you have time, especially on the days you get to read on the train. So you will ideally always have an unread book available for those days.</li>
<li>Big Bang Burger Challenge is really good for stats, just make sure you can pass it before trying. It will give you points in every stat every time you pass it.</li>
<li>USE CHIHAYA!!! When you unlock her you should get her up ASAP as she has super duper useful abilities. Some confidants will have events where you cannot get enough points in order to advance them the next time you hang out, so it will waste time. However with Chihaya you can avoid this completely by using her abilities, specifically her rank 5 one which will increase your affinity with a confidant of your choice, doing this does not advance time and you can use it to avoid having to do extra hangouts with confidants and waste days. Her other abilities are very useful too.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sekiro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sekiro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Sekiro.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Sekiro&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sekiro is a great game with one of the best combat systems in any video game ever. And I’m glad to have played and completed it—and to have &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/watch?v=OXaeOXQwhtkit&#34;&gt;platinumed&lt;/a&gt; it. It is definitely in my top 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-combat&#34;&gt;The Combat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important part of the game, is obviously the combat, and the bosses as well—they go hand in hand. Sekiro’s combat is often described as a dance, and that’s not wrong I don’t think. In the start the abilities at your disposal are basic, but you really don’t need much more to beat the game, there is one ability that should be in your default kit, though I know why it isn’t… that is the Mikiri Counter ability. It is the first ability you will ever get probably and it serves as a way to teach the player about the ability system, so it makes sense that it’s not in your default kit since for most players it will be the first ability they ever acquire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/Sekiro.jpeg" alt="Sekiro"></p>
<p>Sekiro is a great game with one of the best combat systems in any video game ever. And I’m glad to have played and completed it—and to have <a href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=OXaeOXQwhtkit">platinumed</a> it. It is definitely in my top 10.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-combat">The Combat</h2>
<p>The most important part of the game, is obviously the combat, and the bosses as well—they go hand in hand. Sekiro’s combat is often described as a dance, and that’s not wrong I don’t think. In the start the abilities at your disposal are basic, but you really don’t need much more to beat the game, there is one ability that should be in your default kit, though I know why it isn’t… that is the Mikiri Counter ability. It is the first ability you will ever get probably and it serves as a way to teach the player about the ability system, so it makes sense that it’s not in your default kit since for most players it will be the first ability they ever acquire.</p>
<h3 id="endgame-combat">Endgame combat</h3>
<p>Endgame and NG+ combat when compared to how you started out is such a vast difference, with so many abilities at your disposal—you can choreograph fights to basically become cool-ass anime fights, if you’re good enough of course. I’m not that good but I’ve gotten some awesome fights here and there, though if you really wanna see some badass gameplay the YouTuber ONGBAL has a lot…</p>
<p>The amount of abilities at your disposal allows for the most cinematic fights that you’d think came straight from an anime sakuga animator but, you’re literally playing it! It’s actually so fucking cool.</p>
<h3 id="the-bosses">The Bosses</h3>
<p>Long story short, there’s only like 3 bad bosses in the entire game in my opinion. I consider a boss bad if it’s just simply not fun to fight. If I&rsquo;m not looking forward to fighting a boss during a playthrough then it is a bad boss, a good boss I look forward to fighting right from the beginning!</p>
<p>Those three bad bosses are, maybe you’ve already conjectured a guess…</p>
<ul>
<li>The Guardian Ape</li>
<li>The Folding Screen Monkeys</li>
<li>The Demon of Hatred</li>
</ul>
<p>Yeah, who would’ve thought that the three bosses in the sword fighting game that are not about sword fighting would be the worst bosses in the game…</p>
<p>The Folding Screen Monkeys boss fight is just bad and annoying as fuck.</p>
<p>And while I don’t think the guardian ape isn’t the worst it’s still pretty bad… it goes against literally everything that makes this game fun in my opinion and it is stupidly difficult when you first fight it.</p>
<p>And the demon of hatred… there’s not much to say—I cheesed him and then never fought him again.</p>
<h2 id="the-story">The Story</h2>
<p>The story serves its purpose. It’s not the best but it is great for what it is! Obviously the setting is absolutely awesome and the environments and all of that are amazing. Lord Kuro is cool and the other story characters such as Emma are also awesome.</p>
<p>My main gripe would be with the endings and how one of them specifically is like impossibly hard to achieve without looking anything up. You may have not known this but you can eavesdrop on some of the conversations between Lord Kuro and Emma, and this is required for one of the endings… that’s not the bad part though—you can stumble into it, I think I actually did in fact… what is incredibly hard to figure out is that at one point you have to eavesdrop on Emma and the sculptor by going behind the hut in a very specific spot! It wouldn’t be an issue if you didn’t have to be in such a specific spot, but there’s just no way to know that if you don’t look up a guide or SOMEHOW end up stumbling upon it at the right time.</p>
<p>The very last ending (and the one in my platinum video) is the hardest to achieve as you have to kill a secret boss and to do that you have to figure out that you have to backstab and use the puppeteer ability on the enemy in front of the kite in Senpou Temple in order to reach that secret boss—and then you have to know what to do with the Divine Child of Rejuvenation… I don’t know how people originally figured this shit out man.</p>
<p>Yeah that’s it. Bye.</p>
<h4 id="related-articles">Related Articles</h4>
<p><a href="/hidden/sekiro-mechanics/">Sekiro and Pointless Mechanics</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elden Ring: Summons and Delayed Attacks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/elden-ring-delayed-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/elden-ring-delayed-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Elden_Ring.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Elden Ring&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So recently I’ve been playing Elden Ring, and it is incredibly awesome! As of the time of writing this I have clocked in around 32 hours in the game have beaten quite a few bosses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;delayed-attacks&#34;&gt;Delayed Attacks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having played two (technically 3 but Sekiro doesn’t count) other FromSoft games: Bloodborne and Dark Souls 3, I was super surprised by the amount of delayed attacks in the game… basically all of the bosses have some delay to most if not all of their attacks, along with one or two attacks that are INCREDIBLY delayed. It really caught me off guard and I still am not used to it, as in the games I’ve played this was a very rare occurrence—in DS3 I can only think of one boss with delayed attacks and that’s The Nameless King.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/Elden_Ring.jpg" alt="Elden Ring"></p>
<p>So recently I’ve been playing Elden Ring, and it is incredibly awesome! As of the time of writing this I have clocked in around 32 hours in the game have beaten quite a few bosses.</p>
<h2 id="delayed-attacks">Delayed Attacks</h2>
<p>Having played two (technically 3 but Sekiro doesn’t count) other FromSoft games: Bloodborne and Dark Souls 3, I was super surprised by the amount of delayed attacks in the game… basically all of the bosses have some delay to most if not all of their attacks, along with one or two attacks that are INCREDIBLY delayed. It really caught me off guard and I still am not used to it, as in the games I’ve played this was a very rare occurrence—in DS3 I can only think of one boss with delayed attacks and that’s The Nameless King.</p>
<p>Though all that isn’t to say I dislike the delayed attacks, I think they promote more skill expression as you can’t just roll spam to dodge them, you actually have to learn the timings and positioning in order to successfully dodge them which I think is very rewarding. In DS3 you can get away with roll spamming on most bosses but Elden Ring will heavily punish you for it, panic dodging means getting hit for most of your health or even just straight up dying. I do enjoy it.</p>
<h2 id="summons">Summons</h2>
<p>I think summons make the game too easy. I’ve only used them fully on Radahn as I thought, might as well since you’re literally meant to, it’s canon :D.</p>
<p>And I tried using a summon on Margit when I first started playing, however it trivialized the fight so much that I decided right at the end to just jump off the map and kill him without summons—and also decided I wouldn’t use summons for the rest of the game.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sekiro and Pointless Mechanics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/hidden/sekiro-mechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/hidden/sekiro-mechanics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love Sekiro and it is as of the time I’m writing this my favorite FromSoft game. However, while they nailed pretty much everything else I feel like there’s a few pointless mechanics in the game that bug me. I think the most popular one known for being absolutely pointless is the Dragon Rot mechanic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dragon-rot&#34;&gt;Dragon Rot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory it is a cool mechanic that would impact the way you play—if it actually did anything impactful that is. Unfortunately the Dragon Rot mechanic does absolutely nothing it has only once prevented me from doing something in the game—but by that time I was in NG+3 and had enough of the items to get rid of it and continue as normal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I love Sekiro and it is as of the time I’m writing this my favorite FromSoft game. However, while they nailed pretty much everything else I feel like there’s a few pointless mechanics in the game that bug me. I think the most popular one known for being absolutely pointless is the Dragon Rot mechanic.</p>
<h2 id="dragon-rot">Dragon Rot</h2>
<p>In theory it is a cool mechanic that would impact the way you play—if it actually did anything impactful that is. Unfortunately the Dragon Rot mechanic does absolutely nothing it has only once prevented me from doing something in the game—but by that time I was in NG+3 and had enough of the items to get rid of it and continue as normal.</p>
<p>I don’t think it was super thought out. In general merchants and other NPCs don’t do much of anything, so Dragon Rot literally doesn’t change the game other than make the sculptor cough when you go see him—you can still use his services though…</p>
<p>Nobody actually dies from it and the items you need to clear it are rare and are also valuable because they give you extra revives so using them to clear dragon rot is pretty stupid unless you need to do it to do a story-line—which again I only had to do once.</p>
<h2 id="exp-and-unseen-aid">EXP and Unseen Aid</h2>
<p>The EXP mechanics SUCK in Sekiro. The skill trees and scrolls are awesome, but the way the EXP system works I think is pointlessly complicated.</p>
<p>When you die you lose 50% of your experience (and sen), you cannot however lose levels/skill points when you die, you will only lose 50% of your experience for the current level you are at. My main gripe with this is that it doesn’t actually hurt you in any way it just wastes your time if you are trying to get all the skills. There’s no good reason to take away half of your EXP on death, even though it’s not super punishing or whatever it adds a lot of unnecessary farming when you want to get all of the skills.</p>
<p>I think I farmed EXP for a few hours in order to get all of the skills—which is required for the platinum achievement.</p>
<h3 id="unseen-aid">Unseen Aid</h3>
<p>Unseen Aid is probably the most pointless mechanic in this game. It ties in with the Dragon Rot mechanic.</p>
<p>When you die you have a chance to not lose 50% of your EXP and Sen. That’s it. The chance is 30% by default but, it can be changed by dragon rot.</p>
<ul>
<li>Owning one Rot Essence decreases the percentage of Unseen Aid to 15%.</li>
<li>Each subsequent Rot Essence decreases Unseen Aid chance by 2%</li>
<li>Unseen Aid chance can go down to no lower than 2%.</li>
<li>Healing Dragon Rot increases the percentage back to the default of 30%; see the Dragon Rot page for details.</li>
</ul>
<p>This means that it cannot be increased past 30% so it’s basically useless.</p>
<p>Yeah that’s it. Dragon deez nuts on yo face.</p>
<h4 id="related-articles">Related Articles</h4>
<p><a href="/posts/sekiro/">Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sifu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sifu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sifu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Sifu.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Sifu&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;its-just-awesome&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just awesome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sifu is one of the best games I’ve ever played. It’s just genius, the way everything is put together it feels like a game made with so much love and passion. It’s a game with infinite replay-ability—and you’re constantly getting better as you play, the better you get the more fun it becomes. Your first play-through you’re barely figuring out the enemies patterns and struggling to finish the levels without dying—you learn the level and then finally get to the boss at a reasonable age only to die like 10 times just to beat him… but you go on—and by the end you’ve gotten pretty decent, the levels are hard but you can get through them without dying, and you feel confident that you can beat the last boss… I think on my first play-through I got to the last boss at like age 60, and it took a bunch of tries and finally learning how to parry in order to beat him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/Sifu.JPG" alt="Sifu"></p>
<h2 id="its-just-awesome">It&rsquo;s just awesome</h2>
<p>Sifu is one of the best games I’ve ever played. It’s just genius, the way everything is put together it feels like a game made with so much love and passion. It’s a game with infinite replay-ability—and you’re constantly getting better as you play, the better you get the more fun it becomes. Your first play-through you’re barely figuring out the enemies patterns and struggling to finish the levels without dying—you learn the level and then finally get to the boss at a reasonable age only to die like 10 times just to beat him… but you go on—and by the end you’ve gotten pretty decent, the levels are hard but you can get through them without dying, and you feel confident that you can beat the last boss… I think on my first play-through I got to the last boss at like age 60, and it took a bunch of tries and finally learning how to parry in order to beat him.</p>
<p>The satisfaction I felt was immense. And every other boss became a pushover (kinda… Kuroki still kicks my ass lol).</p>
<p>The game’s combat is so incredibly satisfying, and makes you feel like a total badass kungfoo master. It’s really fun stringing together combos and destroying entire groups of enemies in seconds when you get good. And all of the abilities you unlock are incredibly cool and allow for so many play-styles. The game felt completely different at the end when I had all the abilities unlocked, it’s truly freeing.</p>
<h2 id="the-arenas">The Arenas</h2>
<p>The Arenas mode that was added later on via a free update is where you might spend most of your time after beating the game. It takes the arcade style of the game and turns it up to the max&hellip; and it&rsquo;s also really fucking hard, not even master difficulty is as hard as some of these challanges. The gameplay is also varied with different modes—like a TA mode, control mode&hellip; mode where you kill all the targets etc. they really spice things up.</p>
<p>Not only that but there are a lot of new environments and maps to play around in! It&rsquo;s super awesome that all of this came for free with an update! The amount of content here is awesome, especially since you get it all for free!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncharted 2: Among Theives</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/uncharted-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/uncharted-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Uncharted_2.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Uncharted 2&#34;&gt;
Uncharted 2 is a great game that is an improvement on the first in almost every way—story, visuals, and gameplay… not only that but it is also quite a bit longer than the first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, the game looks a lot better than the first—and I would argue that it kind of (not really) holds up today aesthetically, from an art-style perspective at least. The animations all look way better and all of that is great. But I don’t wanna just wanna make comparisons to the two games constantly because that’s boring—so I’ll just list the big differences here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/Uncharted_2.webp" alt="Uncharted 2">
Uncharted 2 is a great game that is an improvement on the first in almost every way—story, visuals, and gameplay… not only that but it is also quite a bit longer than the first.</p>
<hr>
<p>First of all, the game looks a lot better than the first—and I would argue that it kind of (not really) holds up today aesthetically, from an art-style perspective at least. The animations all look way better and all of that is great. But I don’t wanna just wanna make comparisons to the two games constantly because that’s boring—so I’ll just list the big differences here.</p>
<ul>
<li>Game is longer</li>
<li>Crushing difficulty is easier</li>
<li>Story is better.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="-gameplay-">✨ Gameplay ✨</h2>
<p>The gameplay is the main thing I really enjoyed about the game—obviously. My first play through, was obviously on crushing difficulty… gotta get that <a href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=XIChj3ESokk">plat</a>!</p>
<p>The game was challenging on crushing but it wasn’t totally unfair… though there were times where I was super bored of the fighting and just wanted to get it over with—but kept dying because… I was super bored of the fighting and wanted to get it over with. Now most of the game doesn’t have encounter after encounter—the start of the game does, starting at chapter 4… but after a few more chapters the encounters become less. That is until you get to chapter 19-21-ish where at that point it is essentially just fighting for the most part—some puzzle solving here and there but it is a lot of fighting in between that and platforming.</p>
<h3 id="gunplay">Gunplay</h3>
<p>The gun play feels a little bit… unsatisfying—it feels like you’re shooting blanks or nerf darts at the enemy, and it’s not helped by the fact that the weapons you’ll be using the most—that being the ARs: the AK and the M4. These two are probably the worst culprits in my opinion, they are just too inaccurate and are only good to spray down enemies with. Spraying down enemies is most of what you’ll be doing, at least on crushing difficulty and below. Most of the enemies have helmets preventing them from dying from one headshot, and even if they don’t the hit-boxes are kind of atrocious; a lot of the time I would feel as though an enemy should have died but in fact they were alive and then they would one shot me with a shotgun or something. The weapons I had the most luck with were the 92FS and the FAL, as well as the shotguns and of course the RPG and Grenade Launcher were great too when I had access to them though I did find myself not using them as much as getting another weapon after running out of ammo mid fight was kind of annoying.</p>
<p>The good weapons just don’t have enough ammo to make them worth while most of the time, like the Deagle and the Wes, which are both 1 shot kills on unarmored enemies each have a very limited ammo capacity—which makes sense they would be very OP if you could use them as much as the AK or the 92FS… but because of that I never found it worth while to pick them up unless I was fighting a stronger opponent like an armored enemy or something. And even then blind firing from cover was a way better strategy a lot of the time. Especially when fighting certain enemies like the armored guys with shotguns or the shield guys.</p>
<p>Oh yeah the blind fire is actually really good.</p>
<p>I think the weapons I would pick up the most on crushing are these—in order of best to worst:</p>
<ul>
<li>92FS</li>
<li>Sniper Rifle</li>
<li>FAL</li>
<li>RPG</li>
<li>Grenade Launcher</li>
<li>M4</li>
<li>AK</li>
<li>Any of the shotguns</li>
<li>Deagle/Wes</li>
</ul>
<p>The shield is fun but the amount of times that you get to use it throughout the games is a number you can count on one hand so…</p>
<p>On a different note, the cover system, while an improvement over the first game—can feel very clunky as the controls are quite unintuitive and Nate controls like a fucking tank sometimes, I found myself dying a lot while trying to get into cover but Nate wouldn’t do it or would lock onto something completely different. Some pieces of cover worked really poorly and Nate wouldn’t “stick” to them so well, you could walk a bit too far and he would leave cover.</p>
<p>I found myself unintentionally jumping back and forth between cover like poles and such a lot because the controls are kind of unintuitive.</p>
<p>Overall the gunplay is lacking in some areas but it’s not the worst—definitely doesn’t ruin the experience and it is probably the biggest part of the experience for me as well. Encounters were usually very fun and challenging in a mostly unfrustrating way. The AI is not super duper stupid and actually try to flank you and can be a pain in the ass to deal with sometimes—I faced this in chapter 4.</p>
<p>The main issues in my experience are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Guns are unsatisfying</li>
<li>Enemies can be bullet sponges</li>
<li>Cover system can feel clunky at times</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="stealth">Stealth</h3>
<p>Unlike the first game—this one does actually have some stealth which makes the game quite a bit easier as you can start encounters with 4-5 guys already dealt with which is a big help! Some small encounters can even be completely circumvented through stealth which is nice—however the big big encounters, there’s some stealth you can do but at a certain point you do have to do it the loud way.</p>
<p>Overall not bad I don’t think.</p>
<h3 id="treasure-collecting">Treasure Collecting</h3>
<p>There are a total of 101 treasures in the game and they were quite fun to collect. I used a guide—it’d be very hard to get them without one…</p>
<p>The treasures are spread around pretty evenly throughout the whole game, and their locations are pretty off the beaten path this time. Some of them are right in front of you but those are fewer. A lot of the treasures you have to shoot down from a higher up place before you can actually go and collect them which is an OK mechanic though I had one time where a treasure seemingly disappeared after I’d shot it down, reloading checkpoint fixed it though and I was able to collect it.</p>
<p>The rewards you get for them are pretty awesome, the selectable weapons and tweaks are to be expected but what I found quite nice were the skins—compared to the first game. There are more skins, and the ones that change your appearance from Drake to some other character also change your voice, and the even the enemies’ voice lines. For example if you play with the Elena skin you’ll have Elena’s voice during gameplay—including quips like when you pick up a new weapon and stuff like that, and not only that but the enemies’ lines will also change to match your current appearance: “She’s here!” “I got her” instead of the equivalent for Drake. And if you use the donut Drake skin his voice is pitched down which sounds funny.</p>
<h2 id="story">Story</h2>
<h4 id="spoilers-ahead">Spoilers Ahead!</h4>
<p>Uncharted 2’s story is a big improvement on the previous game. The story has Nate and Chloe searching for the lost city of Shambala. Big bad guy is also looking for it. Overall a great story with another supernatural twist at the end.</p>
<h3 id="writing">Writing</h3>
<p>The one thing I found was better was the writing, lots of fun quips and stuff like that—like <a href="https://youtu.be/1wXoG0Li11w">this famous line</a>, or in chapter 4 or 5 if you go into the rooftop pool Nate and Chloe do the Marco Polo thing—or in the chapter with the big statue where you first use the dagger, if you go into the water there’s dialogue for that too.</p>
<h3 id="chloe">Chloe</h3>
<p>Chloe is a pretty cool character—it was a surprise to me that Nate didn’t end up being betrayed by her… from the start I thought she would betray Nate but it didn’t happen, though Nate still ended up with Elena, which I don’t mind. For most of the game she doesn’t care about others but herself and Nate but like right at the end that changes with Elena which is quite nice… not much of a character arc but her change of heart at the end was still nice.</p>
<h3 id="final-boss">Final Boss</h3>
<p>The final boss was a really fun fight, I did spend like an hour dying to him on Crushing but I found the gimmick to be very fun even though it was frustrating on crushing. On other difficulties it is totally fine and is a very awesome fight that leads to a satisfying ending after wanting to beat the shit out of Lozaravich for so long.</p>
<p>All my thoughts. Bye!</p>
<h4 id="related-articles">Related Articles</h4>
<p><a href="/posts/uncharted-1/">Uncharted: Drake&rsquo;s Fortune Remastered</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/meta/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/meta/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a site that I don’t expect many people to read, it’s mostly just for me to keep track of what video games I’ve played and my thoughts on them—just in a public manner because why not. I’ll try to keep it updated as much as possible because I don’t want to be another person with a “blog” that only has like two posts lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like the site you can message me on discord @ranhya and tell me what you think about it! I’m not really on any other social media so.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Footer_Icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a site that I don’t expect many people to read, it’s mostly just for me to keep track of what video games I’ve played and my thoughts on them—just in a public manner because why not. I’ll try to keep it updated as much as possible because I don’t want to be another person with a “blog” that only has like two posts lol.</p>
<p>If you like the site you can message me on discord @ranhya and tell me what you think about it! I’m not really on any other social media so.
<img src="/images/Footer_Icon.png" alt="img"></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Control</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Control.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Control.jpeg&#34;&gt;
Control is an amazing game with an amazing atmosphere. While a little short I think it suits it well, and after playing it… I think it’s become one of my favorite games I’ve played so far!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You play as Jesse Faden, in search of her brother who was taken away by the FBC (Federal Bureau of Control)… which is basically the SCP foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gameplay&#34;&gt;Gameplay&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gameplay in control is something akin to a metroidvania, just more linear than a game you’d traditionally call a metroidvania. The game while mostly story focused has quite a lot of side content as well, especially with the two DLCs—that being said it’s still quite short. I’ve heard of people finishing the game in like 9 hours. I got the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/watch?v=-ZqxTEynWDY&#34;&gt;plat&lt;/a&gt; in about 19. Finished both the DLCs in 21 I think.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/Control.jpeg" alt="Control.jpeg">
Control is an amazing game with an amazing atmosphere. While a little short I think it suits it well, and after playing it… I think it’s become one of my favorite games I’ve played so far!</p>
<p>You play as Jesse Faden, in search of her brother who was taken away by the FBC (Federal Bureau of Control)… which is basically the SCP foundation.</p>
<h2 id="gameplay">Gameplay</h2>
<p>The gameplay in control is something akin to a metroidvania, just more linear than a game you’d traditionally call a metroidvania. The game while mostly story focused has quite a lot of side content as well, especially with the two DLCs—that being said it’s still quite short. I’ve heard of people finishing the game in like 9 hours. I got the <a href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=-ZqxTEynWDY">plat</a> in about 19. Finished both the DLCs in 21 I think.</p>
<h3 id="gun-play-and-abilities">Gun-play and abilities</h3>
<p>The gun play feels great with quite a few weapons to choose from all very useful for a bunch of different situations. My favorite of them has to be the one introduced in the AWE expansion: Surge.</p>
<p>It shoots grenades that stick to enemies and the ground and you can detonate them at any time you want it’s just a lot of fun.</p>
<p>The abilities you get are also a lot of fun. You get a bunch throughout the game that play into the Metroidvania aspect—where you find yourself being able to access new areas as you unlock more abilities… a dash—ground pound, all of that good stuff. I won’t say more because I do think it’s kind of a spoiler but look forward to them if you do play the game.</p>
<h2 id="story-and-environments">Story and Environments</h2>
<p>The story of the game is great and it keeps you on your toes and wondering, Jesse becomes the director of the bureau after picking up the gun from Trench at the start of the game and the story revolves around her figuring out the bureau’s secrets and finding her brother while working to stop the “hiss.”</p>
<p>The atmosphere of the game is top-tier, it really feels like you just entered the SCP foundation, it‘s dark enough to be vibey but not too dark that it feels gloomy to me. I always hate it when it’s always dark and gloomy without any kind of break from the darkness but control doesn’t have that issue! It definitely feels scary without it being overly dark.</p>
<p>One of my favorite things about the game is actually a specific area—one you visit a couple times throughout the game: <strong>The Ocean View Motel and Casino.</strong></p>
<p><img src="/images/The_Ocean_View_Motel_and_Casino.jpeg" alt="The Ocean View Motel"></p>
<p>It’s a liminal space. In the plot it is used as a sort of security measure by the Bureau. It is just so <em>vibey</em> I absolutely love it. You don’t spend a lot of time in the area throughout the game—obviously since it is a liminal space. But every time I got to go there I would get so excited lol.</p>
<h3 id="jesse-faden">Jesse Faden</h3>
<p>Jesse is the main character of the game obviously, I wanna talk about her a bit because I think she’s cool. She’s very well written and very autism-coded. She’s not overly cautious when she doesn’t need to be and is trusting of people which is great—it makes the atmosphere feel less odd when you know she likes a person.</p>
<h1 id="her-monologuing-and-talking-to-polaris-is-also-super-welcome-and-i-love-her-thought-process-she-feels-like-a-very-well-written-main-character-that-fits-the-role-of-director-very-well-d">&laquo;&laquo;&laquo;&lt; HEAD
Her monologuing and talking to Polaris is also super welcome and I love her thought process. She feels like a very well written main character that fits the role of director very well :D</h1>
<p>Her monologuing and talking to Polaris is also super welcome and I love her thought process. She feels like a very well written main character that fits the role of director very well :D</p>
<blockquote>
<blockquote>
<blockquote>
<blockquote>
<blockquote>
<blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>c7d2d047cec88917d95cd8da9ea31e461f1d64f0</p></blockquote></blockquote></blockquote></blockquote></blockquote></blockquote></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncharted: Drake&#39;s Fortune Remastered</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/uncharted-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/uncharted-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Uncharted_1_Boat.avif&#34; alt=&#34;Uncharted 1 Boat&#34;&gt;
Uncharted 1 is a game that had potential—it’s not perfect but it was good enough; so it got a sequel and the series was born, I think idfk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;platinum-experience&#34;&gt;Platinum Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncharted 1 starts you off right in the action—and that’s indicative of the whole game. Having now beaten the game on Crushing (legit) and acquired the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/wnW1rw-geFU&#34;&gt;platinum&lt;/a&gt;. I have to say, while the game has its flaws, I had a lot of fun doing it!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/Uncharted_1_Boat.avif" alt="Uncharted 1 Boat">
Uncharted 1 is a game that had potential—it’s not perfect but it was good enough; so it got a sequel and the series was born, I think idfk.</p>
<h2 id="platinum-experience">Platinum Experience</h2>
<p>Uncharted 1 starts you off right in the action—and that’s indicative of the whole game. Having now beaten the game on Crushing (legit) and acquired the <a href="https://youtu.be/wnW1rw-geFU">platinum</a>. I have to say, while the game has its flaws, I had a lot of fun doing it!</p>
<p>The main gripe I have with the game, is that there is a LOT of shooting—compared to Uncharted 4.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>The lots of fighting got pretty boring on my first play-through, however—with the absolutely insane difficulty of crushing, I thought it wasn’t <em>as bad</em>. Weird… I know, but I found it very rewarding (and frustrating :D) to finally get through a tough encounter some of which took dozens of tries and strategies.</p>
<p>And the amount of encounters did allow for that, but while I thought it a plus during my crushing play-thorough, I do have to say the difficulty and amount of encounters could definitely get quite stale—</p>
<p>You die in like three shots;
The enemies practically have aim bot, so using the in-game cover system means you have very little time to peak out of cover before you get shot to death—and couple that with whatever the fuck kinda drugs the enemies are taking to literally <strong>dodge your shots</strong> matrix-style… the game can feel super duper punishing and unfair a lot of the time… a lot of my deaths I felt like I had no chance because the enemies just lasered me out of nowhere—it definitely felt like RNG at times whether or not I would die in a section.</p>
<p>That’s only on crushing difficulty though—hard and below are quite fair I think.</p>
<p>I am currently trying to platinum the Nathan Drake Collection, so I have to do Uncharted 2 and 3 next. However I think I might also do a brutal run (probably just going to cheat though) for the collection trophy that requires you to beat the game on brutal.</p>
<h2 id="the-gun-play">The gun-play</h2>
<p>The gun play is overall very satisfying even if it’s a little lacking in terms of… feedback? It’s still very satisfying to hit headshots and the guns don’t feel too bad. Out of all of the weapons the pistols are by far the best feeling and, also probably the strongest, with the shotgun being in second. The rifles, are just way too unwieldy and only really good for blind fire, and even then they’re outclassed by the shotguns in that area as well. So in reality there’s only like 3 guns that are worth using in the whole game</p>
<ul>
<li>All of the pistols besides the submachine gun</li>
<li>The sniper</li>
<li>The shotguns</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="the-collectible-system">The collectible system</h2>
<p>Pretty lacking in my opinion, there are 61 treasures in total, and the way they are placed around the game is pretty boring… you end up getting a lot in the first few chapters and then they’re spread out pretty thin throughout the whole game after that. Most of them are not very far off the beaten path and all you do is walk up to them and pick them up. There’s also certain areas with like 3 or 4 treasures close to each other so they get very heavily penalized for proximity. That being said they’re not the worst, and you can totally miss them it’s not like they’re in plain sight.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-story">The Story</h2>
<h3 id="spoilers-ahead-dont-read-if-you-dont-want-to-be-spoiled-i-guess"><strong>Spoilers ahead! Don’t read if you don’t want to be spoiled I guess.</strong></h3>
<p>Uncharted 1’s story, is nothing special but I think it is pretty good for the first game in the series.</p>
<p>You have two(three) big bad guys, one bigger and badder than the other, and one bigger and badder than both the others.</p>
<p>You defeat all of them—kinda… (RIP Eddy). I think the big reveal near the end with the treasure was awesome, especially the set-piece with Eddy, though it is a shame to see him die—he was one of the bad guys. I would’ve loved to see him and Nate fight the big bad guy together, I think it would’ve been an awesome ending—because they probably shared a hatred for Roman and the other guy at the end… maybe not enemies to friends… but enemies to allies—would’ve been awesome.</p>
<p>Elena is awesome and I hope to see more of her in 2 and 3, Elena in 4 was also awesome so…</p>
<p>Yeah that’s all my thoughts. Bye!</p>
<h4 id="related-articles">Related Articles</h4>
<p><a href="/posts/uncharted-2/">Uncharted 2: Among Theives</a></p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>I&rsquo;d only played Uncharted 4 to completion as of writing this.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Completion List</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/meta/completion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/meta/completion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a list of the games I have completed—not in any particular order. The games in &amp;ldquo;platinumed&amp;rdquo; are games I have gotten all the achievements for but have not done enough for me to consider them completed 100%.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;100&#34;&gt;100%&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/sekiro/&#34;&gt;Sekiro: Shadow Die Twice&lt;/a&gt; - 85 Hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/hades/&#34;&gt;Hades&lt;/a&gt; - 10th platinum - ~100 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ratchet and Clank - ~30 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk of Rain 2 - ~150 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hollow Knight - ~100 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NieR: Automata - ~45 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/bloodborne/&#34;&gt;Bloodborne&lt;/a&gt; (No DLC) - 150 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn - First platinum - ~60 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/_3bs6to5pm4&#34;&gt;Dishonored 2&lt;/a&gt; - ~63 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dark Souls 3 - ~100 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/uncharted-1/&#34;&gt;Uncharted: Drake’s Fortune Remastered&lt;/a&gt; - 26 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/uncharted-2/&#34;&gt;Uncharted 2: Among Thieves&lt;/a&gt; - 27 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/persona-5-royal/&#34;&gt;Persona 5 Royal&lt;/a&gt; - 135 Hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;platinumed&#34;&gt;Platinumed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/BwJBtOMsYyI&#34;&gt;Dishonored&lt;/a&gt; - 48 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleeping dogs - 90 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/fI7F0vM7USo&#34;&gt;The Witcher 3&lt;/a&gt; - 107 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/sifu/&#34;&gt;Sifu&lt;/a&gt; -  15th platinum - 28 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/control/&#34;&gt;Control&lt;/a&gt; - 19 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/mGco28OXnGE&#34;&gt;Monster Hunter Rise&lt;/a&gt; - 304 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Cat Quest&lt;/a&gt; - 10 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;100% Doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean 100% of the in-game completion (if the game has a counter, or something similar) but rather what I deem to be 100%. e.g. I consider getting all of the confidants in Persona 5 to max to be 100%. Even though the game has a lot of in-game achievements with the new thieves&amp;rsquo; den area introduced in Royal.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a list of the games I have completed—not in any particular order. The games in &ldquo;platinumed&rdquo; are games I have gotten all the achievements for but have not done enough for me to consider them completed 100%.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<h2 id="100">100%</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="/posts/sekiro/">Sekiro: Shadow Die Twice</a> - 85 Hours</li>
<li><a href="/posts/hades/">Hades</a> - 10th platinum - ~100 hours</li>
<li>Ratchet and Clank - ~30 hours</li>
<li>Risk of Rain 2 - ~150 hours</li>
<li>Hollow Knight - ~100 hours</li>
<li>NieR: Automata - ~45 hours</li>
<li><a href="/posts/bloodborne/">Bloodborne</a> (No DLC) - 150 hours</li>
<li>Horizon Zero Dawn - First platinum - ~60 hours</li>
<li><a href="https://youtu.be/_3bs6to5pm4">Dishonored 2</a> - ~63 hours</li>
<li>Dark Souls 3 - ~100 hours</li>
<li><a href="/posts/uncharted-1/">Uncharted: Drake’s Fortune Remastered</a> - 26 hours</li>
<li><a href="/posts/uncharted-2/">Uncharted 2: Among Thieves</a> - 27 hours</li>
<li><a href="/posts/persona-5-royal/">Persona 5 Royal</a> - 135 Hours</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="platinumed">Platinumed</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://youtu.be/BwJBtOMsYyI">Dishonored</a> - 48 hours</li>
<li>Sleeping dogs - 90 hours</li>
<li><a href="https://youtu.be/fI7F0vM7USo">The Witcher 3</a> - 107 hours</li>
<li><a href="/posts/sifu/">Sifu</a> -  15th platinum - 28 hours</li>
<li><a href="/posts/control/">Control</a> - 19 hours</li>
<li><a href="https://youtu.be/mGco28OXnGE">Monster Hunter Rise</a> - 304 hours</li>
<li><a href="">Cat Quest</a> - 10 hours</li>
</ul>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>100% Doesn&rsquo;t necessarily mean 100% of the in-game completion (if the game has a counter, or something similar) but rather what I deem to be 100%. e.g. I consider getting all of the confidants in Persona 5 to max to be 100%. Even though the game has a lot of in-game achievements with the new thieves&rsquo; den area introduced in Royal.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elden Ring</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/elden-ring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>nasurei22@gmail.com (Nasu Rei)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/elden-ring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Elden_Ring.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Elden_Ring.jpg&#34;&gt;
Elden Ring is by far the biggest game FromSoft has made to date and it is also my favorite as of writing this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it has every aspect I loved about the other souls games I played but by like boosted like 10 times. I think, these games are at heart, Metroidvanias and Elden Ring feels most like one. The open world and literally do anything whenever you want nature of the game make this game feel way more like a Metroidvania than the others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/Elden_Ring.jpg" alt="Elden_Ring.jpg">
Elden Ring is by far the biggest game FromSoft has made to date and it is also my favorite as of writing this post.</p>
<p>I think it has every aspect I loved about the other souls games I played but by like boosted like 10 times. I think, these games are at heart, Metroidvanias and Elden Ring feels most like one. The open world and literally do anything whenever you want nature of the game make this game feel way more like a Metroidvania than the others.</p>
<p>There’s so much to do and see that you could do many playthroughs without even seeing certain areas that other players ended up seeing at the very beginning or other stuff like that. That gives the game a lot of replay-ability along with the amount of build variety you can have, you can just play the game for thousands of hours casually and still not get bored.</p>
<p>There are like over 130 bosses in the base game which is insane—and most of them are good bosses too, very fun fights.</p>
<h2 id="the-open-world">The Open World</h2>
<p>The Elden Ring open world is absolutely massive, I don’t believe the 79 square kilometer estimate is very accurate but it works see: <a href="https://youtu.be/XWQtJiQ1Sm4">this video</a>. But compared to other games the map is absolutely massive and the amount of stuff there is to do in the open world is insane. There’s still so many areas in the open world that I haven’t seen probably which is crazy.</p>
<p>The main way you traverse this massive open world is obviously, with your trusty steed, Torrent. Torrent moves way faster than your character does but to be honest he does feel a bit slow at times, the travel time between graces and certain close areas feels kind of annoying.</p>
<p>An example of that is the way to the Academy Glintstone Key from South Raya Lucaria Gate is deceptively long.</p>
<p>Though travel times aren’t really that big of a deal the main thing that sucks when exploring the open world is</p>
<p><strong>THAT YOU CAN NEVER OPEN YOUR MAP WHEN YOU NEED TO</strong></p>
<p>It is so infuriating when you’re looking for an item or a dungeon or something and you just cannot open your map to check where the fuck you are because some random enemy 3000 meters away is still aggroed onto you, it is so bad. I don’t know what FromSoft was thinking when they made you unable to open the map in combat. Worse decision they’ve ever made. You could argue that it’s to prevent you from fast traveling when in combat but they could’ve just disabled fast travel in combat and that would’ve been a better way to deal with it.</p>
<h2 id="gameplay">Gameplay</h2>
<p>The gameplay loop in Elden Ring is a lot different than the other games FromSoft has made, in my opinion. The core of it is still the same, explore, kill bosses, find key items, get an ending.</p>
<p>But the gameplay loop in Elden Ring focuses a lot more on exploration than the other games, obviously with such a massive open world it’s not a surprise that the game is very focused on exploration—but it’s not just the fact that the game has an open world, the game also has A LOT of dungeons to explore. Not just legacy dungeons but optional dungeons which you will spend a lot of time exploring.</p>
<p>This is also where the Metroidvania aspect of the game comes in, with so much to explore, on subsequent play-throughs the most fun part of the game is coming up with a build, going to the places, getting the weapons and the items and all of that. Upgrading your weapons and trying to optimize your build is very fun. I am a big fan of routing so it’s pretty cool.</p>
<h3 id="the-npc-quests">The NPC Quests</h3>
<p>So, I wanna talk about the NPC quests a bit since I think Elden Ring improves <em>a lot</em> on them, compared to the other games completing the NPC quests is a lot easier without any sort of guide.</p>
<p>There’s not a lot that will lock you out of certain NPC quests and it is a lot more obvious what you’re supposed to do in them. In general you’d ignore quests in these games but in this game specifically I think they’re worth at least trying to do as they’re not too complicated.</p>
<p>Ranni’s quest is the most important quest in the game as certain areas are locked behind it essentially so doing it is imperative, plus you get a cool ending if you do it. The game does an ok job of making it obvious that Ranni is an important character for the most part since you see her right at the start of the game.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
